玄黄端现 太极混沌如鸡蛋
ln the beginning, there was darkness...
随着轰的一声
and then, bang...
诞生了无限膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence...
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
现在所见超乎我们的想象
Now, see further than we've ever imagined...
超越了客观认知极限
beyond the limits of our existence...
那地方我们称之为"宇宙"
in a place we call "The Universe."
它刚柔并济
lt is both mighty and meek.
人类的追求 既要利用其影响 又要摆脱其束缚
Humanity's quest is to harness its power and escape its bonds.
哇塞
Holy cow!
这就是宇航员的感受
This is what an astronaut feels.
它缔造并破坏恒星 行星 星系
lt creates and breaks the stars, the planets, the galaxies...
控制着它们的宇宙过山车驾乘
and directs their cosmic roller coaster ride.
万有引力是亦友亦敌
Gravity is ourfriend and ourfoe.
没了它我们熟知的生命的将不复存在
Without it, life as we know it would end.
地球将人间蒸发
The Earth would literally explode.
伟大而神秘之力
lt is the magnificent and mystifying force...
支配着宇宙 万有引力
that rules the universe: Gravity.
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制:春树  字幕来源:五羊皮  调校:御雪寒狼  招募Q号:76846146
[历史频道] 第二季 第十七集 重力
[History Channel] The UniverseⅡ 17of19 Gravity
万有引力是宇宙间最普遍的力
Gravity is the most pervasive force in the universe.
其作用事无巨细 无一例外
lt is at work on massive and minute scales...on the routine and the extreme.
冲浪者靠它乘风破浪
A surfer needs it to hang ten.
你驾驭浪潮 会乘势而下
When you ride a wave, you're going to slide down the front...
会利用重力往前驰骋
and you're going to use that pull of gravity to get you going.
它使你加速
lt's your acceleration force.
它是你的加速器 重力是你的加速器
lt's your accelerator. Gravity is your accelerator.
滑雪者利用它纵身滑下山坡
A skier uses it to race downhill.
滑雪者必须依靠它来腾空跃起
A snowboarder must have it to get big air.
它作用于具有质量的一切东西
包括我们 无时无刻
lt acts on everything with mass, including us, 24/7...
无论是睡着还是站着
even when sleeping or standing.
地球的万有引力 当然啦 总是将我们
Gravity here on Earth, of course, is always accelerating us down...
拉向地球的中心 加速度为每秒每秒32英尺
toward the center of the Earth at 32 feet per second squared.
在游乐园里 万有引力翻江倒海
At a theme park, gravity is the galactic gas...
让过山车咆哮 人们狂叫
that makes roller coasters roar and people scream.
地球引力把我们拉下
The gravity of the Earth pulls us down...
让我们跑得飞快
and that's going to make us go really, really fast.
所有具有质量或能量的物体
All objects with mass or energy...
粒子 人们 行星 恒星 星系
particles, people, planets, stars, and galaxies...
都会产生引力
produce gravity.
无所不能 无处不在
Omnipotent and omnipresent...
万有引力吸引着 管控着 弯曲着 塑造着 制造着
gravity attracts, governs, warps, shapes, makes...
攫取着宇宙间所有的物质
and takes all matter and mass in the universe.
它无处不在
So it's pervasive.
它远距离影响着一切物体
lt acts on all things through extremely large distances...
无一幸免
and nothing escapes its pull.
是万有引力将我们的太阳系维系在一起
lt is gravity that holds our solar system together.
引力就是将我们紧抓在地球上
The force of gravity...is basically that thing that holds us on the planet...
不让飞离的东西
keeps us from flying off.
它是宇宙胶合剂 将宇宙间的所有物质结合在一起
lt is the cosmic glue that binds all matter in the universe together.
你想过没有 拿两颗骰子
lfyou were to imagine taking two dice...
将其完全静止在太空中
and putting them perfectly at rest out in the middle of space...
两者保持一公分的距离
and separating them by a centimeter...
接下来你会看到 经过一小时左右
then what you'd see is that over a course of an hour or so...
那两颗骰子会慢慢地靠拢在一起
those two dice would slowly come together and touch.
万有引力缔造了我们的世界
Gravity made ourworld.
我们的太阳形成于引力收缩的气体云
Our Sun formed from a vast cloud of gas...that gravitationally contracted.
同样 我们的地球也形成于粒子之间的引力作用
Similarly, our Earth formed through the gravitational attraction...of little particles, little bitty things...
小不点逐步成长为越来越大的物体
gradually growing into a bigger and bigger object.
说到万有引力
When it comes to gravity's pulling power...
质量与距离是必须要提的
mass and distance matter.
它取决于物体的质量
lt depends on the masses of each object...
即物体中的物质总量
the amount of matter within each object.
它与两个质量的乘积成正比
So it's proportional to the product of the two masses.
也就是说 它越大
ln otherwords, the bigger it is...
对其它物体施加的拉力就越强
the harder it pulls on other objects.
不过还不止这样
But that's not all.
它与物体之间距离的平方成反比
And it's inversely proportional...to the square of the distance between them.
就是说 如果你将两个物体之间的距离加倍
This means ifyou double the distance between two objects...
其引力或拉力就只有原来强度的四分之一了
the attraction or pull is only a quarter of its original strength.
万有引力的拉力会控制所有物质的运动或移动
The pulling power of gravity lets it direct the motion and movement...
不管其在宇宙中有多大
of all matter, however massive, in the universe.
所以 你会看到所有的星系 比如
So you have whole galaxies, for example...
相互围绕着
in orbit around each other.
星系团都围绕着它们共同的重心运转
Clusters of galaxies all orbit around their common center of mass.
然而 利用这个无情的力量的实际潜能
But it is the practical potential of harnessing this relentless force...
数百年来一直困扰着科学家
that has obsessed scientists for centuries.
真正开始于伽利略 17世纪的真理追求者
lt would literally fall to Galileo Galilei, the 17th-century truth-seeker...
首次认识到了引力的存在
to first recognize that gravity even existed.
伽利略发现不同重量的物体
Galileo found that objects having a different weight...
下降的速度相等
fall at the same rate.
这里有个很重的钢球
So here's a very heavy steel ball...
这是个同样大小的乒乓球
and a light ping-pong ball of the same size.
如果我同时将它们落下
And if l drop them at the same time...
它们会在同一时间着地
they hit the ground at exactly the same time as well...
因为它们下降的速度相同
because they fall at the same rate.
为了解释伽利略最深刻的万有引力发现
To illustrate Galileo's most profound gravitational discovery...
即所有物体 无论其质量如何 下降速度相同
that all objects, regardless of mass, fall at the same rate...
我们将乘上超快的"超人:逃亡"
we take a ride on the mega-fast "Superman: The Escape"...
位于南加州六旗魔法山乐园
at Six Flags Magic Mountain in Southern California.
这个乐园过山车是自由落体精彩表演的舞台
The theme park ride is the stage...for a spectacular free-fall demonstration.
它将上演满满一车人
lt will showwhat happens when a carfull of people...
与一个网球从高空415英尺处落下的情景
and a tennis ball fall from 415 feet in the air.
好 出发
Okay. Here we go. All right.
噢 天哪
Oh, my. Oh, my God.
乘客以100英里的时速射向41层楼高
The riders are shot up the 41-story-tall tower...at a hundred miles an hour.
由于他们两眼睁开 重力会帮助他们看到超人
With their eyes open, gravity will help them see a superhero.
噢 天哪
Oh, my God. Okay.
现在我将落下这个球
l'm going to drop this ball now and...
噢 天哪 它飘起来了
Oh, my God, it's floating around!
飘起来了
lt's floating! lt's floating!
这时 风把球吹开了
Oh, the wind blew the ball away that time.
虽然 我们预计所有的物体都会自由落下 无论轻重
While we expect all objects to fall freely together, regardless of mass...
不过在大风天 结果总是不太理想
on a windy day, results aren't always perfect.
好 天哪
All right. Oh, my God.
在过山车的顶端 上升运动停止后
At the very top of the ride, when upward motion has stopped...
重力接手了 自由落体开始了
gravity takes over and the downward free fall begins.
我将放开这个球
l'm going to drop this ball...
它飘起来了 飘起来了
and it's going to float. lt's going to float.
噢 飘起来了 飘起来了
Oh, it's floating. lt's floating.
我现在将放开这个球
l'm going to release this ball now.
下来是得意忘形的瞬间
And then, for a few blissful seconds...
乐园里寻求刺激的人们感到了失重
theme park thrill-seekers feel weightless...
仿佛失去了重力 也就是科学家所谓的零重力
as ifthey are free of gravity, or in what scientists call zero-G.
噢 好一个漂浮
Oh, that one floated well. That one floated well.
噢 我将尝试抛下这个球
Oh, l'm going to try dropping the ball.
不过零重力只是个假象
But zero-G isjust an illusion.
实际上 重力掌控着这个过山车
ln reality, gravity is running this ride.
它就是猛拉过山车 人 网球的力量
lt's the force that yanks the car, the people, and the tennis ball...
不管其质量如何 以同样的速度将它们拉回地球
indifferent to their mass, back down to Earth at the same rate.
噢 真是个奇妙之旅
Oh, that's a fantastic ride.
我是说 感觉自己落下真是太惊喜了
l mean, feeling oneself drop is amazing.
不过最了不起的就是球的落下
But what's really great is dropping the ball...
我看到它在我面前飘了起来
and seeing it floating above my face.
我的意思是 它落下了 我知道它落下了
Now...l mean, it's falling. l know it's falling...
不过我也以完全一样的速度落下
but l'm falling at exactly the same rate.
并不在乎物体有多重
lt doesn't matter how massive something is.
落下 在重力作用下 速度完全一样
lt falls, under the force of gravity, at exactly the same rate.
多亏了这样的实验
Thanks to experiments like this...
我们现在知道了物体落下速度是一样的
we now know that objects all fall at the same rate.
那么炮弹发射入轨又是怎么回事呢？
But what would it take to launch a cannonball into orbit?
英国著名的物理学家艾萨克·牛顿爵士
When the famous British physicist Sir lsaac Newton...
看到苹果落下时 有人说是砸中了他的头
saw the apple fall that, some say, hit him on the head...
改变了世界
it changed the world.
你看到苹果从树上掉下
You got the apple falling from the tree...
他抬头看到月球围绕着地球运转
and he looks up and sees the Moon in orbit around the Earth...
判定不光是苹果掉向地球
and judges that not only is the apple falling to Earth...
月球也一样掉向地球
so too is the Moon.
但是月球真的在掉下来吗？
But could the Moon really be falling?
装弹
Load!
通过思考大炮以及它所发射的炮弹轨迹
By thinking of a cannon and the trajectory of the ball it shoots...
牛顿利用数学揭开了一个宇宙之谜
Newton used math to unlock a cosmic mystery.
1687年 它被收进了他划时代的书籍《数学原理》
lt came in his landmark publication, "Principia Mathematica," in 1687.
牛顿有一幅著名的图画
lsaac Newton has a famous drawing...
其中 他画了一个行星 一座小山
and in it, he draws a planet and a little mountain.
有个小炮弹从山上射出
There's a little projectile first kicked off the mountain...
距离不长就落下了
and it falls down a little bit.
你给它更多一点速度 它就更远一些
You give it more speed, it goes a little farther out.
现在就只管增加你想要的力量
Now say you could just increase the force all you wanted.
它可以跑出50英里 100英里后才落下
lt can go fifty miles, it can go a hundred miles before it fell.
只要加上更多的火药 加上适当的发射角度
By adding more gunpowder and withjust the right angle offire...
就可以让炮弹跑得更快更远
a cannonball can be made to go faster and farther.
然而 重力终将胜出
lnevitably, however, gravity wins...
将炮弹拉回地球
pulling the cannonball back down to Earth.
地球是圆的 不是平的 所以牛顿意识到
The Earth is round and not flat, so Newton realized...
假如炮弹发射的速度足够的话
that if the cannonball is fired at sufficient speed...
炮弹实际上就会进入轨道
the cannonball would actually go into orbit.
要做到这一点 牛顿确定
For that to happen, Newton determined...
炮弹从大炮射出
the ball would need to be shot out of the cannon...
速度要达到每小时1.75万英里
at17,500 miles an hour.
它开始弯曲 围绕地球
lt starts curving around the Earth...
他意识到 必定到了一个速度
and he realized that there must be a speed...
它就会一路围绕地球
where it goes completely around the Earth...
打中你的后脑勺
and hits you in the back of the head...
实际上并不会打中地面
never actually hitting Earth's surface.
如果你闪开 它就会一路往前
And ifyou duck, it'll just keep going...
你瞧 看到了一个轨道
and lo and behold, you have an orbit.
不过为何月球没有掉向地球呢？
But why doesn't the Moon fall to Earth?
月球也有一些横向运动
The Moon also has some sideways motion...
所以 它每掉下一点点
so for every little bit that it falls down...
也会在这个方向离开一点点
it also moves off in this direction...
这些运动加在一起就是围绕地球的轨道
and the sum of all those motions is an orbit around the Earth.
牛顿同样意识到地球也是围绕太阳的大自由落体
Newton also realized that the Earth is in a giant freefall around the Sun.
由于引力打造了轨道 我们地球围绕着太阳
With gravity forging the path, our planet rounds the Sun...
就像是永不停顿的宇宙过山车
like an endless cosmic roller coaster ride.
牛顿破解了引力之谜
Newton cracked the gravity code...
物理学家现在依然沿用他的思想来解决各种问题
and physicists are still using his ideas to solve all sorts of problems...
其中一些出奇的怪
some ofthem stranger than others...
比如 要是有人打个隧道 从地球的一头
like, what would happen if a person tried to travel through a tunnel...
穿到另一头 会是个怎样的情形？
from one side of the planet to the other?
在这个疯狂的计划中
ln this wild scheme...
你将要驱车穿越地球的直线隧道
you would have to drive a straight-line tunnel...
就利用重力来推动旅客
right through the Earth and use gravity alone to propel a traveler...
进入这个所谓的重力快车
down this so-called gravity express.
所以 假设你有一个这样的隧道
So, suppose you've got one ofthese tunnels...
你跳了进去
and youjump in.
一开始 地球把你拉下去
lnitially, the Earth is pulling down.
你将一路奔向地心
You're going toward the center of the Earth...
你在加速奔向它
and so you're accelerating toward it.
然而你一旦过了地心
But as you pass through the center ofthe Earth...
开始奔向另一端时
and start going out toward the opposite side...
地球的重力又试图将你拉回去
the gravity ofthe Earth is trying to pull you back...
所以是在减速
so it's decelerating you.
所以 重力其实是在发挥制动作用
So gravity's actually having a braking effect.
无需担心在地球的另一端射出洞口时速度极快
There's no fear of shooting out the hole...on the other side of the Earth at some tremendous velocity...
而把你射进太空
and shooting yourself back into space...
不过事实上 你刚好到达地表
but, in fact, you reach the surface ofthe Earth exactly.
你将会滑行到完全静止
You would coast to a perfect rest.
42分钟 你就可以抵达那里
ln forty-two minutes, you'd be there.
无论你用直线隧道连接哪两座城市
Whichever two cities you connect with a straight-line tunnel...
重力都会用上精确的42分钟将你带到那里
it takes gravity exactly forty-two minutes to get you there.
从洛杉矶到巴黎 42分钟
Thejourney from Los Angeles to Paris, forty-two minutes.
假设你从洛杉矶前往东京
Suppose you wanted to go from Los Angeles to Tokyo...
42分钟
forty-two minutes.
它并不在乎你穿越地球的路径
lt doesn't matterwhich path you take through the Earth.
行程总是42分钟不变
Thejourney is always forty-two minutes long.
用牛顿的数学来搞明白其原理吧
lt takes Newton's math to figure out why this works.
如果我们连接洛杉矶到纽约
lfwe connect Los Angeles to NewYork...
挖个隧道 显然
digging a tunnel, obviously...
隧道不是笔直往下
a tunnel would not go straight down...
而是往下需要一个角度
but it has to go down at an angle.
这个角度减缓了下降的速度
The angle slows the speed of descent.
不过距离也减短了
But the distance is also less.
要是你解出这个方程式
And ifyou work out the equations...
瞧 两个效应抵消了
lo and behold, the two effects cancel...
你到那里还是42分钟
and you still get there in forty-two minutes.
需要42分钟 不管你走哪条路
lt takes forty-two minutes regardless of the path you take.
酷呆了
That's really cool.
牛顿搞明白了重力的作用
Newton figured out what gravity does...
然而却让才华横溢的爱因斯坦
but it took the brilliance of physicistAlbert Einstein...
来解决它为何会如此的
to work out why it was doing it.
爱因斯坦意识到恒星 行星之类的大物体
Einstein realized that gravity is really caused by huge objects...
所产生的引力 其实是在弯曲空间本身
like stars and planets, literally bending space itself.
宛如巨大的橡胶板
Like a massive rubber sheet...
空间被其中的大物体弯曲了
space is curved where massive objects sit in it.
事实上 爱因斯坦提出 行星围绕恒星的路径
ln fact, Einstein proposed that the path planets take around their stars...
它们的轨道 全都是这个空间弯曲的直接结果
their orbits, are all a direct result of this curvature of space.
他声称 所谓的轨道
He said that what an orbit is...
其实就是物体在直线上运动
is really something traveling in a straight line.
物体自由落向另一个物体时
When something is free-falling towards another object...
其实就只是穿行于时空中的直线
it really isjust traveling in a straight line through space-time.
不过 时空的弯曲将其路径弯曲成了封闭的轨道
However, the curvature of space-time bends its path into a closed orbit...
而空间本身将其弯曲回来
but space itself curves it back in on itself.
这个革命性的发现是爱因斯坦在1910年代提出的
This revolutionary discovery came when Einstein, in the early1910s...
当时已经认识到了恒星及行星在可见的宇宙间的轨道
realized that orbits of stars and planets in the observable cosmos...
其表现就像牛顿计算所预测的
behavejust as Newton's math predicted...
除了一个:水星
except one: Mercury.
其轨道很不稳定
lts orbit essentially wobbles.
爱因斯坦把引力描述成时空的弯曲
Einstein described gravity as a curvature in space and time...
水星的轨道恰是你对此考虑的理想对象
and the orbit of Mercury works perfectly when you take that into account.
水星并不是运行在平平的空间 而是弯曲了太阳周围的空间
Mercury isn't moving in flat space, but curved space around the Sun.
所以其轨道是很完美的
Then the orbit's perfect.
空间的这种弯曲是我们太阳系里的拿手好戏
This curvature of space is at play in our own solar system.
地球只是循着自以为的直线路径
Earth is simply following what it thinks is a straight-line path...
在本质上是弯曲的空间中两点之间的最短距离
the shortest distance between two points...in this intrinsically curved space.
爱因斯坦不仅确定了质量弯曲了空间
Einstein not only determined that mass warps space...
同时也弯曲了时间
it warps time, too.
因而 爱因斯坦宣称从今之后
So, henceforth, Einstein proclaimed...
物理学家不应该孤立看待空间与时间
physicists should not speak of space and time separately...
而是要将时空作为一个整体
but of space-time as one unified object.
虽然许多人首次听到很不舒服
While it's uncomfortable to many the first time you hear it...
不过你仔细想想 其实是很有道理的
ifyou stop and think about it, it's actually quite obvious.
如果你与某人有个约会
lf l'm going to make an appointment with somebody...
我可不会说 我在3:00与你碰头
l don't say, "l'll meet you at 3:00."
这个信息并不充分
That's not enough information.
下来还有一个问题
There's got to be a question that follows that.
什么问题？
What is that question?
哪里？
Where?
要是我说 203室碰头
lf l say, "Meet you in room 203."
何时？
When?
某时你与某人见面
Any time you intersect with someone's else's life...
你就确定了时间和地点了
you do so at a time and at a place.
爱因斯坦对空间是弯曲的领悟
Einstein's realization that space is curved...
时间与空间实际上是交织在一起的
and that time and space are, in fact, intertwined...
现在已经成了万有引力的精确定义了
is now the very definition of gravity.
发现号升空
Liftoff of the Space Shuttle "Discovery."
揭开万有引力的秘密
Unlocking the secrets of gravity...
已经让人类解脱了世俗的枷锁
has enabled humanity to escape our earthly shackles...
打开了宇宙探索之门
and opened the universe for exploration.
但是 如何才能让未来的宇航员长途跋涉前往火星
But how can future astronauts on the long way to Mars...
度过零重力造成的危害呢？
survive the disabling effects caused by zero-G?
万有引力是我们的朋友
Gravity is ourfriend...
亦是我们的敌人
and ourfoe.
它是令人生畏的力量 驱动滑雪者
lt is the fearsome force that propels a skier...
纵身滑下山坡
and the snowboarder down the mountain...
腾空跃起
and shoots them into the air.
有了足够的动能 飞翔的滑雪者
With enough momentum, an airborne snowboarder...
可以感受到驰骋的一刻
can feel forfleeting moments...
宛如克服了地球的引力
as if they are free of Earth's gravitational pull.
你跃身跳起时 实际上失重了
You're actually weightless when you go offthejump.
失重的时间取决于与你的速度相关的轨迹长度
The period ofweightlessness is determined...by the duration ofyour trajectory as a function ofyour velocity...
因而滑雪者一个漂亮的腾空翻
so that the snowboarder who gets really good big air...
可以获得1秒 2秒甚至3秒钟的失重
may achieve a second, two seconds, even three seconds ofweightlessness.
然而最后 还是重力胜出
But in the end, gravity wins...
高高跃起 自由落体的滑雪者
and the high-flying, free-falling boarder...
就像是大炮射出的炮弹
just like the ball fired from the cannon...
终将被拉回地球
is eventually yanked back down to Earth.
滑雪者的这个自由落体
This free fall for the snowboarder...
他或她腾空跃起之时
as he or she goes over thejump...
划出一道轨迹 犹如炮弹那样的自由落体
and creates this trajectory isjust as much free fall...
划破天空
as a cannonball going through the air...
轨迹就取决于速度和重力
and the trajectory is determined...only by the velocity and the force of gravity.
然后 当然啦 落地又是另一回事了
Then, of course, what happens on the landing is another story.
然而 倘若滑雪者追求达到更高的高度又如何呢？
But what if a snowboarder...aspired to reach even greater heights?
倘若他想克服重力
What if he wanted to overcome gravity...
将自己抛离地球有会怎样呢？
and launch himself right off the planet?
你想一劳永逸地离开地球吗？
You want to leave Earth entirely and forever?
地球拥有我们所谓的逃逸速度
Earth has what we call the escape velocity...
这种魔术速度就是一旦你过了这个速度
this magic speed where ifyou pass that speed...
你就会永远逃离地球 一去不复返了
you will escape Earth forever, never to return.
逃逸速度 任何物体都需要达到的最小速度
Escape velocity, the minimum speed any object needs to reach...
以挣脱地球
in order to escape from the Earth...
是每秒7英里左右的速度
is about seven miles a second.
也就是时速2.5万英里
That's 25,000 miles an hour.
理论上 要是一个滑雪者
ln theory, even a snowboarder...
具有足够的冲力 对着正确的方向
with enough momentum and aimed in the right direction...
也可以向火箭那样飞起来
can take offjust like a rocket.
摆脱地球的引力对滑雪者来说也许是不现实的
Escaping Earth's gravity may not be realistic for a snowboarder...
但是事实证明可以将人或火箭射入轨道
but it has proven possible to launch people and projectiles into orbit.
你可以离开系统
You can leave systems.
你只需足够的力量就可以做到
Youjust need enough energy to do so.
我们已经积累了足够的能量和技术
And we've garnered enough energy and technological know-how...
已经在前往月球时做到了
to dojust that in ourvoyages to the Moon.
我们希望继续前往火星乃至更远
And our hope is that that will continue on to Mars and beyond.
为了去火星乃至更远
To get to Mars and beyond...
人类必须利用万有引力的能量
mankind will have to harness gravity's energy...
就像我们在追求极限的刺激中一直做的
just like we always do when we're seeking thrills to the extreme.
万有引力给了我们两种力量
Gravity gives us two types of energy...
势能和动能
potential...and kinetic.
势能就是那个
Potential isjust that.
就是储存的能量
lt is energy that's being stored...
此时动能就是积蓄在势能里的所有结果
while kinetic is the result of all that pent-up potential energy.
这种神奇的现象在过山车上发挥了作用
This fantastic phenomenon works on a roller coaster.
随着你被拉上高坡 你的势能也在增加
As you're winched up on a hill, your potential energy is increasing.
你在过山车顶部的势能要大过在底部
You literally have more energy...at the top of the roller coaster than at the bottom.
这不只是离奇抽象的东西
lt's notjust a weird, abstract thing.
你在顶部具有较高的能量
You actually possess higher energy at the top...
那会转化成速度 动能
and that's turned into speed, into kinetic energy...
只要你坐着过山车溜下高坡
as you go down that hill on the roller coaster.
很快 我就会将我的势能转换成动能
Pretty soon, l'll be converting my potential energy to kinetic energy.
冲浪者位于浪潮的甜蜜点时
When a surfer hits that sweet spot on a wave...
他们会利用能量的双重效应
they're using energy's double act.
航天局同样利用这个能量转换法则
NASA also uses this energy exchange principle...
为任务增加一些速度
to add some speed to their missions.
飞船接近行星轨道时
As a spacecraft nears the orbit of a planet...
它同样会提高动能 牺牲势能
it, too, gathers kinetic energy at the expense of potential energy.
然后随着它坐上宇宙过山车绕过行星时
Then as it rounds the planet on its cosmic coaster ride...
飞船就会获得一个弹弓效应
the craft gets a slingshot effect...
利用更大的动能来推动它
that punches it onward with more kinetic energy.
1979 1980年旅行者号拜访木星时
When the Voyager spacecraft visited Jupiter in 1979, 1980...
飞经木星 木星牵引着它
it flew past Jupiter, and Jupiter tugged on it...
给了它额外的动力 就好像弹弓效应
giving it extra motion, sort of a slingshot effect...
不光改变了它的运动方向
not only changing its direction of motion...
使得它奔向土星
so that it was aimed towards Saturn...
同时还加速了它
but also speeding it up.
懂得利用万有引力的力量
Knowing how to use the power of gravity...
将让人类在宇宙间走的更远更快
will enable humanity to travel further and faster across the universe.
有了成熟的物理学和可用的科技
Having the physics formulated and the technology available...
还只是外星旅行准备的一部分
isjust one part of the preparation for extraterrestrial travel.
让人准备应对恶劣的太空则是另一方面
Readying people for the rigors of space is the other.
远离地球的引力
Far away from Earth's gravitational pull...
呆在飞船里长途跋涉前往火星 举个例子
in a spaceship on the long journey to Mars, for example...
未来的宇航员将必须学会生活 工作 玩耍
future astronauts will have to learn to live, work, and play...
在无地球重力的环境中
in an environment free of Earth's sizeable gravity...
在那里 他们切实感受到失重
one where they effectively feel weightless...
所有物体的运动都无拘无束
and all objects move equally and freely.
体验宇航员惊险刺激的太空之旅的一个有趣方法
One fun way to experience...the astronautical thrills and spills of space travel...
就是在零重力飞行中进行模拟
is to simulate it on a zero-G flight.
我热切地期待去体验
l'm really looking forward to this.
这将会是个神奇的体验
This is going to be an incredible experience.
搭乘终极过山车
By riding the ultimate roller coaster...
一架特别改造的零重力波音727飞机
a specially modified zero-G Boeing 727 aircraft...
天体物理学家亚历克斯·菲利潘科即将开始他的人生之旅
astrophysicist Alex Filippenko is about to go on the ride of his life.
这将像空中抛出的球
This is going to be like a ball thrown up in the air...
因为自由落体而失重
weightless because it will be in free fall...
所以 我将四处漂动 没有任何东西支撑
so l'll be floating around as though there's no ground holding me up.
零重力飞机飞行在2.4-3.2万英尺高度
The zero-G flight flies between 24,000 and 32,000 feet.
这相当于普通商业飞机的飞行高度
This is about the same altitude as a regular commercial jet...
但是那是模拟结束的地方
but that is where the similarity ends.
接下来是在平流层里的一系列爬坡滑翔
The water's the next one? The path it follows is a series of coaster-like rolling hills...in the stratosphere.
宛如"超人:逃亡"
Just like "Superman: The Ride"...
超级零重力飞机在45度角爬坡过程中积蓄起势能
the super zero-G plane gathers potential energy...as it climbs up at forty-five degrees.
乘客感受到了加重
Passengers feel this as an increase in weight.
噢 耶
Oh, yeah.
重力的度量是G
Gravity is measured in terms of g-forces.
一个G 就是我们站在地球表面感觉到的万有引力的量
One G is the amount of gravitywe feel...standing on the surface ofthe Earth.
我将回去像这样做好准备
l'm going to get back down like this and get ready.
随着飞机急剧爬坡 加速向上
As the plane steeply climbs, accelerating upward...
重力G在提高 人感觉到加重了
the gravity G count rises and people feel heavier.
好
All right.
飞机带我们加速往上
The plane is accelerating us upwards...
达到了最大值1.8个G
at about1.8 G at its maximum.
随着飞行平稳抵达弧顶
As the flight approaches, then eases around the apex of the arc...
飞机以及机内的所有人
the plane, as well as all the people inside it...
实际上进入了自由落体状态
are, in effect, in free fall.
零重力出现了
Zero-G comin' up.
噢 伙计 难以形容的感觉
Oh, man, what an indescribable feeling.
哇塞
Holy cow!
噢 我身处自由空间
Oh, l'm out in free space.
飘起来啦
Floating, just floating.
这就是宇航员的感觉
This is what an astronaut feels.
飞机的轨迹一再产生失重
The plane's trajectory induces weightlessness again and again...
通过飞出一系列的抛物弧线
by flying a series of these parabolic arcs.
尽管他们都在机舱里
Even though they are within the cabin of a plane...
零重力乘客还是像跳伞那样自由落向地球
the zero-G passengers are freely falling towards the Earth just like skydivers.
但是 究竟是什么造成了失重感的呢？
But what creates the sensation ofweightlessness?
这要追溯到伽利略
lt goes back to Galileo...
是他表明了所有的物体落下的速度相同
who showed that all objects fall at the same rate.
所以 当飞机及其机内人员自由落向地球时
So, as the plane and the people inside fall freely toward Earth...
它们保持着彼此之间的相对位置
they maintain the same position relative to each other...
那就是他们感觉失重的原因所在
and that is why they feel weightless.
这种感觉持续了整整25秒钟
The feeling lasted twenty-five full seconds...
因为在25秒钟里 我们基本上处于自由降落中
because, for twenty-five seconds, we were essentially in free fall.
这就像超人在空中飞翔一样
lt was like Superman just flying through the air.
噢 我无法相信这样的感觉
Oh, l cannot believe how it feels.
飞机重新启动 结束自由落体后
When thejet's engines reengage and end the free fall...
乘客们重新感觉到了自己的重量
the passengers feel theirweight return.
就像爱因斯坦所言 失重只是一种假象
As Einstein would say, weightlessness is but an illusion.
感觉真棒 太棒了
This is so awesome! So awesome!
零重力飞机利用了爱因斯坦的某些东西
The zero-G plane takes advantage...
那是他早在1916年
of something Einstein worked out back in 1916...
他的广义相对论所提出的
in his general theory of relativity...
加速度其实是和万有引力同样的东西
that acceleration is essentially the same as gravity.
在你在火箭或零重力飞机里上升时
When you are thrust upward in a rocket or the zero-G plane...
你所体验到的G(加速度)
the G-forces you experience...
等同于你被行星这样的大物体的引力
are the same as you would feel being tugged downward...
往下拽拉的感觉
by the gravity of a massive object like a planet.
因此万有引力和加速度产生了同样的感觉
So gravity and acceleration create the same sensation.
那就是为何零重力飞机里的乘客
That's how the passengers on a zero-G flight...
可以感受到宇航员的感觉
can feel like an astronaut...
可以体验到失重的乐趣
and can experience thejoys ofweightlessness.
这球和我都在自由落下
The ball and l arejust freely falling...
遵循弯曲时空的自然通道
according to our natural path through curved space-time.
这就是爱因斯坦的理论所言
This is what Einstein's theory says.
无关质量 我们都遵循同样的轨迹
lndependent ofthe mass, we all follow the same path.
噢 耶 简直难以置信
Oh, yeah, this is unbelievable.
20分15秒的抛物线飞行
On the twenty-minute, fifteen-parabola flight...
体验到了进一步嘲弄万有引力法则的惊恐与快乐
there's time in between the frights and delights...to further taunt the laws of gravity.
快看 那水
Look at that. Look at that water.
噢 看那水 我来逮住它
Oh, look at that water. l'm going to catch some.
抓到了
Okay, here we go.
除了招待周末勇士们进行抛物飞行外
As well as entertaining weekend warriors...
还有不吉利叫做"喷发彗星"的
the parabolic flights...also inauspiciously called "The Vomit Comet"...
具有实际的用途
have a practical purpose.
那是准备让航天员在零重力的空间环境中生活工作
They prepare NASA astronauts forworking and living...in the zero-G environment of space.
有了这些耸人听闻的抛物线飞行
With these sensational parabolic flights...
人类学会了如何去模拟失重
humans have learned how to simulate the absence of gravity.
然而 同样有可能在实验室里创造出人造重力吗？
But is it also possible to create artificial gravity in the lab?
这样的实验将引领成功的火星探索
These experiments will lead to a successful exploration of Mars.
就在未来
lt is in ourfuture.
21世纪初 克服重力的束缚
At the dawn of the 21st century, overcoming the bonds of gravity...
摆脱地球的羁绊已经实现
and escaping Earth's sizeable tug have been realized.
下一步就是研发和打造技术
The next step is to design and build the technology...
让人类在其它行星上旅行 工作 生活
that will allow humans to travel, work, and live...on exotic alien planets.
我们已经积累了足够的工程技术
And we've garnered enough engineering know-how...
我们在前往月球就做到了
to dojust that in ourvoyages to the Moon.
得益于先进的科技
Thanks to state-of-the-art technology...
人类站在了太空探索新纪元的前哨
humanity is on the brink of a new era in space exploration.
火星之旅已经在麻省理工学院的这个实验室里开始
The trip to Mars is beginning here at our laboratory at MlT.
人造重力可能是手段之一
Artificial gravity may be one of the ways that we overcome...
让我们克服失重的负面效应
the debilitating effects ofweightlessness.
随着太空时代的来临
Since the advent of the space age...
科学家一直牵挂着将零重力失重带来的
scientists have been concerned with minimizing...
生命威胁的风险和危害影响减到最低水平
the life-threatening risks and damaging effects...of being weightless at zero-G.
这些问题本来就与人类的生存息息相关
The issues originally had to do with human survivability.
我们甚至不知道当时在阿波罗时代
We didn't even know back in the Apollo period...
人们在太空逗留几个小时是如何应对的
how people would react to stays in space...of more than a few hours.
存在着各种担忧
There was all kinds of concern about humans' ability...
人类在经历了长时间的失重后控制飞船的能力
to control a vehicle after being exposed to weightlessness...for a long period of time.
火星任务将要求宇航员
A mission to Mars would require astronauts...
远离地球的引力至少两到三年
to be away from Earth's gravity for at least two, maybe three years.
人类的骨架根本不是为了
The human frame is simply not designed...
对付地球1G重力缺失的
for the absence of terrestrial one-G gravity.
我们人体构架的设计是为了承载我们在重力下的重量
The architecture of our bodies is designed to withstand ourweight...under the forces of gravity.
重力确定了我们心血管系统的反应
Gravity determines how our cardiovascular system reacts...
所以在你起床时
so when you get out of bed...
从躺着到站立
and you go from being supine to upright...
有一个调节系统来保持血压
there's a regulatory system that keeps the blood pressure...
对重力做出反应
reacting against the forces of gravity.
经验表明 长时期处于失重
Experience has shown that being weightless for long periods...
会引发骨质流失 肌肉退化
leads to bone loss, muscle deterioration...
以及危及生命的血栓
and life-threatening blood clots.
航天局和麻省理工的航天工程师
Aeronautical engineers at NASA and MlT...
正在测试个人离心机系统
are testing a personal centrifuge system...
有可能缓解实际危害
that may mitigate the very real dangers.
它们保护心脏 骨骼 肌肉
They protect the heart, the bones, their muscles.
即使在这些初期实验中 我们有充分的理由相信
And even in these early experiments, we have every reason to believe...
短半径离心机产生的人造重力
that artificial gravity with short-radius centrifuges...
有可能是我们所寻找的普遍解药
may be the universal antidote that we're looking for...
以保护人们远足火星
to protect people on the long trip to Mars.
就像游乐场里的木马
Just like a theme park ride...
旋转物体 人造重力
spinning a subject artificially creates g-forces.
为了预防麻省木马乘客的晕车
To prevent motion sickness in the MlT ride...
宇航员将保持头部固定
astronauts are conditioned to keep their head still.
一分钟里把人转上30圈
By spinning a person at thirty revolutions a minute...
离心机产生出一个G
the centrifuge imparts one G...
相当于人站在地球上感觉到的往下拉的力
the same force felt pulling down a person standing on Earth.
科学家希望有朝一日 火星之旅成为现实
Scientists hope that one day, a trip to Mars will be a reality.
他们认为应随机携带个人离心机
Onboard, they believe there should be a personal centrifuge.
为了得到地球重力的补充 21实际的宇航员
To get their Earthly gravity fill-up, 21st-century astronauts...
将只需要每天上机一小时
could then just spend one hour a day on the machine.
我们每天上机一会儿
We get onto it for a brief period every day...
把它飞快转起来
and get spun up quite fast...
就在我称之为旋转健身房里
spun up in what l'll call a spin in the gym.
你去锻炼 去训练
You go foryour exercise, you go foryourworkout...
去滋补G 滋补重力
you get your G tonic, your gravity tonic.
尽管火星之旅还要等上几十年
While a trip to Mars may still be decades away...
天体物理学家 老道的滑雪者拉里·杨
astrophysicist and seasoned skier Larry Young...
梦想着在火星的无拘束重力中来个腾空翻
can dream of big air in the liberating gravity of Mars.
其表面 重力是地球的3/8
On the surface, there is three-eighths the tug of Earth's gravity.
人人都想做些空翻
Everyone likes to get some air.
人人都想露上一手
Everybody likes a little bit.
试想我们到了火星
Just think ifwe were on Mars.
地球上重100磅的人
A person who weighs 100 pounds on Earth...
在火星上就会感觉只有38磅了
would feel as if they weigh 38 pounds on Mars.
纵然火星滑雪者能纵身跃下奥林匹斯山
Although a Martian skier would fly down Olympus Mons...
以在地球上的速度的三分之一
at a third of the speed theywould on Earth...
但是低重力也意味着它们会翻出
the lower gravity also means that theywould get...
至少三倍的空翻
at least three times the big air.
对万有引力而言 质量是前提
ln the case of gravity, it's mass that matters.
你拥有的质量越多 万有引力的力量就越大
The more mass you have, the stronger the pull of gravity.
所以在你考虑地球上的体重时
So when you think about what yourweight would be on the Earth...
对应的是质量超过地球的物体 直截了当
versus something more massive than the Earth, it's pretty direct.
如果物体的质量是地球的两倍
lf something were twice as massive as the Earth...
那么你的重量也将是翻番
you'd weigh about twice as much.
我们太阳系里的大哥大是木星
The Big Kahuna in our solar system is Jupiter.
在那颗行星上 100磅的人
On that planet, a 100-pound person...
将重达254磅
would weigh a whopping 254 pounds.
即使木星上有坚硬的地表
Even if Jupiter had a solid surface...
滑雪者将不得不为空翻而奋斗
a skier there would have to fight for big air.
我们已经了解了万有引力 它的原理
What we already know about gravity, how it works...
它的实际用途
and how it can be used for practical purposes...
可以 理论上甚至还能挽救地球免遭终极厄运
could, in theory, even save the planet...from its ultimate cataclysmic fate.
请看万有引力是如何对我们进行救援的
Here's how gravity can come to our rescue.
渐渐地 在50亿年里
Gradually, in about five billion years...
我们的太阳将增亮膨胀 变成红巨星
our Sun will brilliantly flare, turn into a red giant...
悲壮地走向死亡
gloriously burn up and die.
随之而来的是内太阳系将被吞没
As this comes to pass, our inner solar system is engulfed...
地球的引力极其大气层将被面目全非
and Earth's gravity and atmosphere will be radically altered.
那时 蓝色星球上的生命将告终结
At that point, life on the blue planet will end.
然而天体物理学家格雷格·劳克林有一个打算
But astrophysicist Greg Laughlin has a plan...
利用万有引力来拯救地球
to use gravity to save Earth.
我们现在所处的环境
This environment that we have here now...
看似非常类似于现在金星上的环境
would look very similar to the environment...that is holding sway on Venus right now.
稠密的二氧化碳大气
A crushing carbon dioxide atmosphere...
温度极高足以融化铅
temperatures hot enough to melt lead.
不过稍安毋躁 即使最坏的假设一旦发生
But rest assured, if the worst hypothetical happens...
引力科学可以拯救我们的母亲地球
gravitational science could save mother Earth.
我们在很长时期里可以做的一件事
The one thing that we could do over the very long term...
就是设法迁移地球的轨道
is to somehow move the Earth's orbit...
远离太阳 到温度不高的地方
out to a larger distance from the sun...where the temperature isn't so hot.
有办法做到的 只要你时间充裕
And a way that you can do that, if you have enough time...
假如你有几十亿年的时间
ifyou have billions ofyears available to you...
利用彗星和小行星
is to use a comet or an asteroid.
这种庞大的搬迁需要宇航员和工程师
This mega move would require astronauts and engineers...
搭载飞船去操控彗星或小行星
aboard a spacecraft to maneuver the comet or asteroid...
就放在地球的前面
just in front ofthe Earth.
为了使之最有效
ln order to be most effective...
彗星必须靠地球很近
the comet has to fly very close to the Earth...
就在地球的轨道半径范围内
within orbital radius or so ofthe Earth.
然后搭载宇宙过山车
Then on the cosmic roller coaster...
潜能和动能被激发 而引力就不在话下了
potential and kinetic energy are roused and gravity does the rest.
一旦那样 彗星就会拉着地球往前跑
lf that happens, then the comet pulls the Earth forward...
地球拉着彗星往后跑
the Earth pulls the comet backward...
最终结果就是地球被推进了
and the net result is that the Earth is given a boost.
它会被推进到一个较大的轨道半径
lt's given a boost to a slightly higher orbital radius...
较远离太阳
slightly larger distance from the Sun.
只要你进行一次这样的调整
And ifyou make one of these adjustments...
每一万年前进一次
one of these passages every10,000 years or so...
于是地球 经过10亿年
then the Earth, over a period of a billion years...
就可以以足够快的速度往外迁移
can move at a fast enough pace outward...
与逐渐增亮的太阳保持距离
to keep track with the steadily brightening sun.
但是万一专家计算错误
lf however, the experts get the math wrong...
一着不慎 则全盘皆输
and the big gamble doesn't work, all bets are off.
你稍有闪失 就会发生彗星撞地球
And ifyou screw that up, then you can have a collision...
上百公里的东西撞击地球
between the comet and the Earth. So a hundred-kilometer object crashing into the Earth...
绝对是个难以想象的灾难
is absolutely an extraordinary disaster.
那可是造成物种大灭绝的大事
lt's the kind of thing that causes huge extinctions...of gigantic numbers of species.
当然 这只是极端的假设情况
Of course, this is only an extreme hypothetical scenario...
不过确信无疑的是
but what is known for sure...
我们现在生存在地球上
is that our continued existence today here on Earth...
完全是得益于引力的存在
is contingent on the presence of gravity.
它为生命提供了理想的条件
lt allows for the perfect conditions for life...
和幸福的追求
and the pursuit of happiness.
一个G带来了冲浪者的梦想:完美的浪潮
One G produces the surfer's dream: A perfect wave.
不过玩耍于地球的狂野之水
But the wild waters enjoyed on Earth...
不只是引力产生的浪潮一种
are not the only kind of gravity-generated waves.
还有巨大的宇宙浪潮 席卷着整个宇宙
There are cosmic waves so large they roll across the entire universe.
引力激发的粒子激流席卷宇宙
Tidal torrents of gravity-boosted particles roll across the cosmos.
按爱因斯坦的说法
According to Einstein...
那些引力波涤荡着宇宙
these gravitational waves wash through the universe.
然而那是怎么回事？
But what are they?
引力的任何变化
Any change in the gravity...
都会给空间结构泛起涟漪
sends a ripple through that fabric of space...
接着以光速推进
then moves at the speed of light.
那就是引力波
That would be a gravity wave.
为何会发生的呢？
And why do they happen?
如果你有两个物体 两颗致密的恒星
lfyou have two objects, two compact stars...
每个都会弯曲周围的空间
each ofwhich curves space around them...
它们相互缠绕
and they're orbiting one another...
结果 这两个弯曲的区域
then the result is, is that these two curved regions...
就会产生波 结构里的波纹
create a wave, a ripple in the structure...
在空间里携带能量往外移动
in the shape of space that moves outwards...carrying energy with it.
这就是所谓的引力波
That's called a gravitational wave.
我的意思是 确实你可以把时空里的波
l mean, literally, you can think about space and time...
看作是穿行宇宙的波浪
having a wave, just like an ocean wave in it...that travels through the universe.
引力波就是这回事
Gravitywaves arejust the same.
运动中的物质 无论大小
Any type of mass in motion, big or small...
都会产生引力波
generates a gravitational wave.
犹如地球上的波浪
And like the Earth's ocean tides...
引力波无休止地席卷整个宇宙
gravitational waves roll ceaselessly across the cosmos.
理论上 驰骋太空的冲浪者可以体验到
ln theory, a surfer launched into space could experience...
天堂里的翻滚与蛇行
an out-of-this-world wipeout and warp.
如果引力波产生在太空某处
lf a gravitational wave was created in space or somewhere...
扑面而来 那么结果就会是
and went through you, what would happen...
你变胖了 接着又变瘦了
is you'd get fat and then you'd get skinny...
就是说空间被扭曲了
meaning that space was distorted.
某个方向的空间让你发胖
Space in one direction made you fatter.
而在另一个方向 则在挤压你
ln the other direction, it squashed you.
来来回回
And it goes back and forth.
然而对于脚踏实地侦测微弱引力波信号的科学家来说
But for earthbound scientists to detect any faint G-wave signals...
这种扰动需要由庞大的宇宙物体来传播
the disturbance needs to be propagated...by a massive cosmic object.
黑洞和旋转的中子星能够做到
Black holes and spinning neutron stars can do it.
另一个可以产生引力波的东西
Another thing that can make a gravity wave...
就是爆发 也就是超新星
is an explosion, say, a supernova.
恒星爆发 轰的一下
A star explodes and it goes...whack...
实际上把引力波往外推出
and that actually pushes a gravity wave forward.
捕捉引力波里类似光的信号的工具是LlGO
The tool to catch the light-like signal from a wave is the LlGO...
即激光干涉引力波观察站
the Laser lnterferometer Gravitational Wave Observatory.
有两个一模一样的地面LlGO实验室
There are two identical, ground-based LlGO labs.
一个在华盛顿州的汉福德
One is in Hanford, Washington...
另一个在2000英里外的
and the other is more than 2,000 miles away...
路易斯安那州的巴吞鲁日附近
near Baton Rouge, Louisiana.
如果有引力波经过
lf a wave comes by,
那么两个实验室的结果 对于确认事件都是至关重要的
each lab's results will be vital to confirm the event.
来看看它的原理
Here's how it works.
超级抛光玻璃镜面安装在干涉仪的支架上
Super polished glass mirrors are at the fulcrum of the interferometer...
这个工具基本上是
which is a tool that basically...
对比两束光波的测量成果
compares two light wave measurements...
确认两者之间的差异
and identifies the differences between them.
精准的激光来回发射
Precision laser light is fired back and forth...
分叉对准两个校准的镜面
and split between two calibrated mirrors.
通常情况下 光波上下波动
ln normal circumstances, as the light bounces up and down...
在2.5英里长的L形的真空管里
the 2 1/2-Mile long, L-shaped vacuum tubes...
这两束激光是同步的
the two laser beams are basically in sync.
这意味着这两束激光会相互抵消
This means the beams effectively cancel each other out...
一点都不会逃出管道
and no light escapes the tunnel.
然而当引力波经过时
But when a gravity wave rolls through...
空间会被轻微的伸缩
space is ever so slightly stretched or squashed.
结果激光束会走位
As a result, the laser beams are thrown out of phase...
射出一丁点光束
and only then a small amount of light is emitted...
一个比人发直径还小的信号
a tiny signal, less than the diameter of a human hair...
质子的千分之一大小 会被收集到
1/1000th the size of a proton will register.
转换成声音和光信号 听到看到
Converted into a sound and a light signal...it will be seen and heard.
科学家最大的愿望
The scientists' greatest hope...
就是捕捉到宇宙迄今所发生的最大事件
is to catch the most massive event that ever occurred in the universe...
大爆炸
the Big Bang.
引力波可能是最好的机会 让我们一睹
Gravitywaves may be our best chance to look...
紧接着宇宙诞生的那一刻
very, very close to the beginning of the universe.
大爆炸30万年后
About 300,000 years after the Big Bang...
宇宙异常稠密 乃至混沌一片
the universe was so dense, it was actually opaque to light.
光都难以通过
Light could not travel through it.
那么要是光都难以穿透宇宙 什么能穿透呢？
So if light can't travel through the universe, what can?
引力波
A gravity wave.
问题是引力波发出的微乎其微的信号
The problem is a miniscule signal from a gravitywave...
尚未被捕捉到
has yet to be caught.
显然很困难
lt's clearly hard.
事实上 爱因斯坦预言它们时
自以为是个不错的主意
ln fact, when Einstein predicted them, he thought it was a nice idea...
然而无人能够发现
but no one would ever be able to detect them.
唯有技术的进步才能给我们机会
lt's only the advances of technology that give us a chance.
LlGO的科学家 宛如星际冲浪者
LlGO scientists, like astrosurfers...
活出精彩 乘风踏浪
live for the day when they can hang ten...
面对引力波 迎头而上
and ride theirvery own perfect wave of gravity.
我们看到了 我们认为是引力波的影响
We've seen what we think are the effects of gravity waves...
就是引力波经过的系统里的能量的损失
the loss of energy from a system by way of gravity waves...
但是我们还没有直接发现到
but we never directly detected one.
那是最后的前沿阵地之一
That's one of the last frontiers.
LIGO科学家的探索一旦成功
lf the LlGO scientists' quest is successful...
捕捉到一个引力波的话 那将会改变科学
and they catch a wave, it could change science.
因此 我认为长远来看 首先是了解引力
So, l think that long term, it's first to understand gravity...
其次 更有意思的是了解宇宙
and then, even more interestingly, to understand the universe.
万有引力的领地覆盖我们整个宇宙
The force of gravity has domain over our universe.
它创造并能够毁灭宇宙 恒星 行星 以及人类
lt created and can destroy the cosmos, the stars...the planets, and the people.
它主宰着我们的生活 我们的玩耍 我们的努力
lt controls our lives, our play, and our endeavors.
那就是宇宙芭蕾
And therein is this cosmic ballet.
我们共同的未来取决于宇宙强大的统治者
Our collective future depends on the grace and greatness...
万有引力的恩泽与博爱
of the mighty ruler of the cosmos, gravity.
谢谢观赏
Thanks For Viewing